

ESSAID SERHANI

Orlando, FL 32837 407-808-6553

dias_19@hotmail.com

Portfolio link: http://purelight4ever.github.io

WEB DEVELOPER

PROFILE

A Web developer specializing in front end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including JavaScript, html, CSS, jQuery, NodeJS, Express, phpmyadmin, SQL Server. Quickly learn and master new technology; equally successful in both team and self-directed settings.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Front End Web Developer (Free Code Camp)
- SQL Server DBA (Udemy)
- Real World SQL Server (Udemy)
- > C# .NET Development (Basic & Intermediate)
- Advanced Databases and SQL Querying (Udemy)
- JavaScript (basic, intermediate) (Udemy)
- Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp (Udemy)

LANGUAGES

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, JQuery, AJAX, NodeJS, Express, RESTful, Python, T-SQL, PHP, C#, .Net

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Create website layout/user interface by using standard HTML/CSS/JavaScript/JQuery.
- Advanced HTML scripting, CSS, JavaScript and C# .NET programming.
- Maintain existing web applications, creating and maintaining database tables.
- Experience developing complex web sites using content management systems like WordPress...
- Test applications on various browsers and modify if necessary.
- Strong problem solving and issue resolution skills with attention to details.
- Advanced user interface graphic design skills.
- Self-start with strong self-management and problem-solving skills.
- Demonstrated experience working in a collaborative team environment.
- Ability to multi-task and manage several projects simultaneously.
- Knowledge of image authoring & editing tools, to be able to crop, resize and enhanced...
- Known for excellent problem-solving skills and patience in dealing with frustrated users.

WORK HISTORY

Programmer, COGNIZANT.CO, Tampa, FL	01/2017 – Present.
Web developer, MPNA.CO, Orlando, FL	06/2012 – 12/2016
Desktop Technical Support, AMERICAN RING TR.INC, Orlando, FL	04/2006 – 06/2012
Substitute Musician Performer, WALT DISNEY WORLD.CO, Orlando, FL	06/1999 – 10/2016

EDUCATION

ISTA. University, ASSOCIATE DEGREE.
Free Code Camp, FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER